<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Past Projects | MSCE Lab</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/past_projects/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/past_projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Past Projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:15:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/logo_hu5524306541054396158.png</url>
      <title>Past Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/past_projects/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling reactive transport in porous media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/past_projects/reactive_porous/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/past_projects/reactive_porous/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Membrane technologies for water purification </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/past_projects/mem_spacer_optim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 23:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/past_projects/mem_spacer_optim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Membrane-based desalination processes, such as reverse osmosis and membrane distillation, have become widely used for water recovery in recent years. However, these processes face challenges such as membrane fouling due to polarization caused by concentration and temperature gradients. In this project, we aimed to address this challenge by using high-fidelity simulations to gain a comprehensive understanding of mass and heat transport in membrane-based desalination systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through our simulations, we investigated the effects of various parameters on the transport properties of these systems, including
operating conditions, and reactor designs. Our findings will provide quantitative guidelines for the design and operation of membrane-based desalination processes to improve their efficiency and minimize fouling. Specifically, we provide insights into optimal operating conditions to reduce fouling and polarization effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, our project provides a valuable contribution to the field of membrane-based desalination, offering a deeper understanding of mass and heat transport in these systems and providing practical guidelines for improving their design and operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- In recent years, membrane has been widely used in different technologies to recover water through desalination. Typical processes
include but not limited to reverse osmosis and membrane distillation. One challenge associated with these membrane-based
technolgoies is membrane fouling due to polarization (both concentration and temperature). In this project, we employed
high-fidelity simulations to understand the mass and heat transport in these systems to provide quantitative guidelines for design
and operation.  --&gt;
&lt;!-- 

















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;MD_abstract.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale heat transfer in a battery pack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/past_projects/battery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 23:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/past_projects/battery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Battery packs undergoing thermal runaway pose a serious safety hazard, and accurate modeling of these systems is crucial for system design and safety. However, the multiscale nature of these systems presents a significant challenge, as accurately resolving spatial and temporal scales spanning multiple orders of magnitude is computationally intensive and pushes the limits of theoretical models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, we developed a non-intrusive two-way coupled hybrid algorithm for simulating heat transfer in battery packs undergoing thermal runaway. Our hybrid algorithm combines fine-scale (cell-scale) and continuum-scale (battery pack-scale) models in the same numerical simulation to achieve predictive accuracy while keeping computational costs manageable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We developed two methods with different orders of accuracy to enforce continuity at the coupling boundary, and derived weak
formulations of the fine-scale and upscaled governing equations for numerical implementation in FEniCS. Through our simulations, we
demonstrated that our hybrid algorithm can accurately predict the average temperature fields within errors determined by
homogenization theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./gifs/Fine-Scale-One-Sided.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./gifs/Hybrid-Taylor-One-Sided-30.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./gifs/Hybrid-Series-One-Sided-30.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-thermal-runaway-of-a-battery-pack-fine-scale-hybrid-with-taylor-hybrid-with-series-and-upscaled-packing-temperature&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./gifs/Upscaled-Packing-One-Sided.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Thermal runaway of a battery pack: Fine-scale, Hybrid with Taylor, Hybrid with Series, and Upscaled packing temperature.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Thermal runaway of a battery pack: Fine-scale, Hybrid with Taylor, Hybrid with Series, and Upscaled packing temperature.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, we demonstrated the computational efficiency of our hybrid algorithm against cell-scale simulations, highlighting the significant computational savings achieved without compromising the accuracy of the simulation results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project presents a significant advancement in the field of battery pack modeling, providing a non-intrusive hybrid algorithm that can accurately simulate thermal runaway in these systems. Our findings have important implications for battery pack design and safety, providing a valuable tool for improving the efficiency and safety of these systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Accurate analytical and numerical modeling of multiscale systems is a daunting task, since the need to properly resolve spatial and temporal scales spanning multiple orders of magnitude pushes the limits of both our theoretical models as well as our computational capabilities.  Battery packs undergoing thermal runaway are one such example. While the thermal front&#39;s characteristic spatial scale may be at the scale of single cells, accurate predictions of its dynamics through the entire battery pack is critical to guide the overall system design. Classical approaches to model thermal runaway in battery packs include the use of coarse-grained macroscopic models, which describe the spatially-averaged response of the system. However, such models may become inaccurate if appropriate dynamic conditions are not met. Hybrid models that combine fine-scale (cell-scale) and continnum-scale (battery pack-scale) models in the same numerical simulation can achieve predictive accuracy while keeping computational costs in check. Here, we present a non-intrusive two-way coupled hybrid algorithm for simulating heat transfer in battery packs. 

Two methods with different orders of accuracy are developed to enforce continuity at the coupling boundary, and weak formulations of
the fine-scale and upscaled governing equations are derived for numerical implementation in FEniCS. We demonstrate that hybrid
simulations can accurately predict the average temperature fields within errors *a priori* determined by homogenization
theory. Finally, we demonstrate the computational efficiency of the hybrid algorithm against cell-scale simulations. --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy-positive wastewater treatment systems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/past_projects/prs_ww_optim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 23:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/past_projects/prs_ww_optim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Staged Anaerobic Fluidized-bed Membrane Bioreactor (SAF-MBR) is a promising technology for reducing the energy intensity of domestic wastewater treatment by using anaerobic microorganisms to convert organics into methane in the absence of aeration. However, the hydrodynamic processes related to flow-particle and particle-particle interactions induced by the moving particles in the SAF-MBR are poorly understood, which hinders its design and operational practices.&lt;/p&gt;











  





&lt;video controls  &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/past_projects/prs_ww_optim/videos/p0200_10_20x.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address this issue, we have developed a collocated particle resolved simulation (PRS) using the immersed boundary method (IBM) to accurately quantify the fluid-particle and particle-particle interactions in a fluidized-bed reactor. Through our simulations, we have investigated the effect of particle Reynolds number and found that an intermediate particle Reynolds number regime exists where the combined effect of flow and collisions is optimal, maximizing both mixing in the AFBR and membrane scouring in the P-MBR.&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-hypothetical-impacts-of-upflow-velocity-and-porosity-on-fluidized-bed-reactor-modeling-design-and-operation&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./figures/Flow_Effect.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hypothetical impacts of upflow velocity and porosity on fluidized-bed reactor modeling, design and operation.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Hypothetical impacts of upflow velocity and porosity on fluidized-bed reactor modeling, design and operation.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also determined that the design of fluidized beds critically depends on the Archimedes number, which combines the effect of particle and fluid properties. Our simulation results show that particles with an Archimedes number greater than roughly 1000 should be used to avoid flow short-circuiting due to clusters in the AFBR and reduced membrane scouring due to ineffective collisions in the P-MBR.&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-hypothetical-impacts-of-particle-properties-and-archimedes-number-on-fluidized-bed-reactor-modeling-design-and-operation&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./figures/Archimedes_Effect.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hypothetical impacts of particle properties and Archimedes number on fluidized-bed reactor modeling, design and operation.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Hypothetical impacts of particle properties and Archimedes number on fluidized-bed reactor modeling, design and operation.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, our simulations reveal that segregated layers of particles behave identically to their corresponding monodispersed fluidized bed layers, but the transition region between the two segregated layers cannot be described as a simple superposition of the two segregated layers. Overall, our findings provide valuable insights into the hydrodynamics of the SAF-MBR and can help improve its design and operation for more efficient and effective wastewater treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Recently, the Staged Anaerobic Fluidized-bed Membrane Bioreactor (SAF-MBR), which consists of an anaerobic fluidized-bed reactor
(AFBR) and a particle-sparged membrane bioreactor (P-MBR), has been developed to reduce the energy intensity of domestic wastewater
treatment by using anaerobic microorganisms that convert organics into methane in the absence of aeration. While this has the
potential to transform domestic wastewater treatment into an energy positive process, the moving particles in the SAF-MBR induce
hydrodynamic processes related to flow-particle and particle-particle interactions that are poorly understood. With a better
understanding of hydrodynamics, better design and operational practices can be developed. 












  





&lt;video controls  &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/past_projects/prs_ww_optim/videos/p0200_10_20x.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;


To overcome this, a collocated particle resolved simulation (PRS) using the immersed boundary method (IBM) is developed to
accurately quantify the fluid-particle and particle-particle interactions in a fluidized-bed reactor.We first investigate the effect
of particle Reynolds number which is essentially a nondimensional flow rate that controls the bed expansion. Results imply the
existence of an intermediate particle Reynolds number regime at which the combined effect of flow and collisions is optimal and both
mixing in the AFBR and membrane scouring in the P-MBR are expected to be maximized. 



















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-hypothetical-impacts-of-upflow-velocity-and-porosity-on-fluidized-bed-reactor-modeling-design-and-operation&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./figures/Flow_Effect.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hypothetical impacts of upflow velocity and porosity on fluidized-bed reactor modeling, design and operation.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Hypothetical impacts of upflow velocity and porosity on fluidized-bed reactor modeling, design and operation.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


While the Reynolds number is a critical parameter, the design of fluidized beds depends critically on the Archimedes number that
combines the effect of particle and fluid properties. Simulation results reveal that particles with Archimedes number greater than
roughly 1000 should be used to avoid flow short-circuiting due to clusters in the AFBR and reduced membrane scouring due to
ineffective collisions in the P-MBR. In industrial applications, fluidized beds typically contain particles of different sizes that
tend to segregate into layers in which the particle size increases moving
upward. 



















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-hypothetical-impacts-of-particle-properties-and-archimedes-number-on-fluidized-bed-reactor-modeling-design-and-operation&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./figures/Archimedes_Effect.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hypothetical impacts of particle properties and Archimedes number on fluidized-bed reactor modeling, design and operation.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Hypothetical impacts of particle properties and Archimedes number on fluidized-bed reactor modeling, design and operation.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


Our simulations reveal that segregated layers behave identically as they would in their corresponding monodispersed
fluidized bed layers. However, the transition region between the two segregated layers cannot be described as a simple superposition
of the two segregated layers --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nitrous oxide recovery from sidestream wastewater</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/past_projects/cando/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 23:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/past_projects/cando/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The release of nitrogen from wastewater into natural water bodies can lead to eutrophication and the formation of oxygen-depleted zones, which can have significant impacts on aquatic ecosystems. Conventional nitrogen removal processes typically require a large amount of energy for aeration, reducing power, and disposal of waste biosolids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research aims to address these issues through the development of shortcut nitrogen removal processes, which involve the
oxidation of ammonium to nitrite, followed by the reduction of nitrite to nitrous oxide using either heterotrophic denitrifiers. To
recover energy while removing nitrogen from wastewater, we have developed a dual-stressor partial nitritation process with timed
alkali addition, followed by the Coupled Aerobic-anoxic Nitrous Decomposition Operation (CANDO) process, which recovers nitrogen in
the form of nitrous oxide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach has several advantages over conventional nitrogen removal methods. The dual-stressor partial nitritation process is robust and can operate at high ammonia concentrations, while the CANDO process enables the recovery of nitrogen in the form of nitrous oxide, which can be combusted with methane to generate energy. In addition, this process requires less energy input than conventional methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our findings suggest that the use of nitrous oxide in energy generation has significant potential for sustainable wastewater treatment, and we hope that our research will contribute to the development of more efficient and sustainable processes for nitrogen removal from wastewater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Release of reactive nitrogen from wastewater into natural water bodies can stimulate eutrophica-
tion and create oxygen-depleted zones. Conventional nitrogen removal processes need significant energy input for aeration, require
reducing power, and generate large amount of waste biosolids for disposal. These issues can be addressed through shortcut nitrogen
removal processes in which ammonium is oxidized to nitrite, and nitrite is reduced to dinitrogen gas with either heterotrophic or
autotrophic denitrifiers. To recover energy while removing nitrogen from wastewater, we first developed a robust dual-stressor
partial nitritation process with timed alkali addition and then Coupled Aerobic-anoxic Nitrous Decomposition Operation (CANDO)
process to recover nitrogen in the form of nitrous oxide. Nitrous oxide has been proven to improve energy generation when combusted
with methane. --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
